# **Spencer Lindemuth**

Inspired developer with passion for creating engaging, easy to use websites. Use of Agile programming principles to be efficient and successful while remaining flexible in an ever changing industry. Leads with bright personality and 8 years of technical background in web design, graphic design, information technology, and systems administration.

#### TECHNICAL PROJECTS

### CSSchool - Github | Website

A website designed to teach CSS basics to people of all ages in an interactive learning environment

- Utilized React to create a guiz-based learning environment teaching CSS to beginners to intermediate students
- Built feature allowing users to dynamically generate custom lessons through an HTML form
- Developed program to be seamlessly used on mobile using CSS media queries
- Constructed Rails backend API to serve lessons and handle JWT authentication

#### Hi-Lo - Github | Website

A turn based, two player game based on the popular card game Acey Deucey

- Created multiplayer game with pure javascript frontend and game logic
- Deployed app to accrue over 100 games played by more than 50 unique users
- Optimized game to play effortlessly on desktop and mobile

# Artsy Fartsy - Github | Website

A website that allows users to create their own digital gallery of select works from the MET™ museum

- Designed React app using React-Draggable to place and persist pieces on gallery wall
- Employed MET OpenAccess API™ to find public domain works to browse and add to gallery
- Utilized a mix of traditional and on trend design elements to create an engaging experience for modern users

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Comprehensive knowledge in functionality and design using Javascript, React, HTML/CSS, Adobe Photoshop, Lightroom and XD. Backend developer in Rails with deployment and management experience on Heroku, Azure, Godaddy, Plesk, and Netlify.

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### Hotel Monaco, Seattle, WA

Valet/Doorman - January 2016 - May 2019

- Organized team to consistently exceed guest expectations of service in this luxury boutique hotel
- Developed friendly, welcoming presence with which to great guests upon arrival
- Performed exemplary retrieval times for cars and luggage which maintained a clear and orderly lobby and parking zone

#### Northside Networks, Mesa, AZ

I.T. Support/Systems Administration, October 2012 – May 2014

- Delivered 24/7 quick response services for more than 40 small businesses simultaneously
- Maintained excellent record of minimizing and preventing downtime and loss of business
- Deployed Small Business Servers for user management, email, hosting, and content distribution
- Mastered a working knowledge of computers, servers, networking equipment and other hardware and how they function

# Clearcut Marketing Concepts, Mesa, AZ

Junior Developer, June 2011 - October 2012

- Bridged the work of a front end developer and back end developer as both a stylist and additional developer on a dynamic, three person, full-stack team
- Utilized CSS to style PHP front-end e-commerce websites
- Integrated seamlessly into an existing small team to guickly and reliably create content

# **EDUCATION**

# Flatiron School - Seattle, WA - 2019

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript/React immersive course

# University of Michigan - Ann Arbor, MI - 2010-2012

- Computational Informatics (2 years toward B.S.)
- Achieved intermediate proficiency of Python and beginner proficiency with C++